河南省二零二三年普通高中
招生考试。
第一节，听下面五段对话，每段。
对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
Well, I did want to go to the music club, but I like painting better, so I will join
the painting club.
But the weather report says it will be this afternoon.
What a terrible day!
It's been raining for a long time.
Yes, but the weather report says it will be sunny this afternoon.
粽子
Stephen, what do you like most about China?
food. I just had zongzi on a dragon boat festival.
What is your favorite food?
Jiaozi is my favorite.
It's really delicious.
Kevin is hurt.
Will he be able to finish the game?
No, his arm is really bad.
Okay, I'll go and tell the team.
Kevin is hurt.
Will he be able to finish the game?
No, his arm is really bad.
Okay, I'll go and tell the team.
听下面一段对话，回答第六至。
第七，两个小题。
What's up, Jenny?
is going to be a school speech competition next Friday.
My teacher asked me to give a speech, and I'm preparing for it.
Good for you.
What are you going to talk about?
I haven't decided yet.
I'm thinking about language learning.
Why not talk about environmental protection?
That's a good topic.
I'll go and find some information.
Thank you for your advice.
No problem. What's up, Jenny?
There is going to be a school speech competition next Friday.
My teacher asked me to give a speech, and I'm preparing for it.
Good for you.
What are you going to talk about?
I haven't decided yet.
I'm thinking about language learning.
Why not talk about environmental protection?
That's a good topic.
I'll go and find some information.
Thank you for your advice.
No problem. Sure.
听下面一段对话，回答第。
第八至第九两个小题。
Go along Road and turn right on Renmin Road.
花园
Then you will see a shopping center.
The bookstore is across from it.
Is it far from here?
Kind of. You can ride a shared bike.
Look, there's one over there.
Thank you. Excuse me, where can I find a bookstore?
Oh, there's one on Renmin Road.
you please tell me how to get there?
Sure. Go along Road and turn right on Road.
花园
人民
Then you will see a shopping center.
The bookstore is across from it.
Is it far from here?
Kind of. You can ride a shared bike.
Look, there's one over there.
Thank you. Boys and may I have your attention please?
听下面一段独白，回答。
十至第十二三个小题。
There will be a special activity in our school hall this afternoon.
We will invite a fireman to come and tell us how to keep safe when a fire happens.
The talk starts at three o and ends at four o
After that, we will go out to the playground.
The fireman will show us how to put out a fire safely.
Be careful not to stand too close to the fire while watching.
That's all. Thank you.
Boys and girls, may I have your attention please?
There will be a special activity in our school hall this afternoon.
We will invite a fireman to come and tell us how to keep safe when a fire happens.
The talk starts at three o and ends at four o
After that, we will go out to the playground.
The fireman will show us how to put out a fire safely.
Be careful not to stand too close to the fire while watching.
That's all. Thank you.
fireman show to safely.
听下面一段对话，回答第十三。
至第十五三个小题。
Julie, have you read the book we talked about last time?
Yes, it's great.
I really like the boy named Scott in a story.
Me too. I think Scott is really brave.
I totally agree with you.
I heard the writer will come to our city to meet fans at the library.
Do you want to go with me?
Sure. When shall we meet?
Let's make it nine a.m.
this Saturday. Where shall we meet?
At the school gate.
Okay. See you.
Julie, have you read the book we talked about last time?
Yes, it's great.
I really like the boy named Scott in a story.
Me too. I think Scott is really brave.
I totally agree with you.
I heard the writer will come to our city to meet fans at the library.
Do you want to go with me?
Sure. When shall we meet?
Let's make it nine a.m.
this Saturday. Where shall we meet?
At the school gate.
Okay. See you.
第三节：听下面一篇短文，按照你所听内容的先后顺序，将下列图片排序
短文读。
读两遍。
Our class went on a school trip last Saturday.
We got on the bus at eight o and it took us one hour to get there.
After we arrived, we bought the tickets and took a photo together.
Everyone looked very happy in the photo.
Then we began to climb the mountain.
When we got to the top of the mountain, we were very tired.
We took out the food, drinks and fruits and had a nice picnic.
At the picnic, we shared a lot of interesting stories.
After that, we cleared the area and took all the rubbish away.
At around three o in the afternoon, we started to head back.
We were so happy that we sent songs all the way back.
What a wonderful day.
Our class went on a school trip last Saturday.
We got on the bus at eight o and it took us one hour to get there.
After we arrived, we bought the tickets and took a photo together.
Everyone looked very happy in the photo.
Then we began to climb the mountain.
When we got to top of the mountain, we were very tired.
We took out the food, drinks and fruits and had a nice picnic.
At the picnic, we shared a lot of interesting stories.
After that, we cleared the area and took all the rubbish away.
At around three o in the afternoon, we started to head back.
We were so happy that we sent songs all the way back.
What a wonderful day.
英语听力考试到此结束，
请同学们将听力答案转涂到。
答题卡上，然后继续做笔试部分的题目。
When to the